In this section we'll learn a way to tell overfitting,
在本节课中 我们将学习一种判断过拟合、
underfitting, and a good model.
欠拟合、 和好模型的方法
So here we have our data three times.
这里我们有三份完全一样的数据
Our data seems to be well split by a quadratic equation of degree two.
我们的数据似乎能被二次方程很好地分类
So we're going to try and fit three models.
这里我们要尝试拟合三个模型
The first one a linear or degree one model which
第一个是
doesn't do a very good job since it underfits.
欠拟合的线性模型
So it's a high bias model.
所以它是个高偏差模型
The second one, a quadratic model of degree two,
第二个是二次模型
which is just right and the third one a higher
它拟合的正合适  第三个
degree polynomial of degree six which overfits,
是一个过拟合的6阶多项式模型
So it's a high variance model.
所以它是个高方差模型
Now we'll draw some curves that we'll be able to tell these models apart.
现在我们将画一些曲线 它们将帮助我们区分这些模型
So let's start here with a high bias linear model.
让我们从这个高偏差线性模型开始
We're going to start training the model with
开始时 我们先用很少的点训练这个模型
very few points and increase the number of points gradually.
然后再逐渐增加点数
So if we train this model with say four points,
如果我们用四个点来训练模型
we can do a pretty good job fitting the training set.
我们可以很好的拟合这个训练集
So we have a tiny training error,
所以训练误差很小
which we'll plot in the graph in the right.
我们将在右边的图表中绘制出来
But once we evaluated on the cross-validation data well,
但是如果我们用交叉验证集来检验模型
since we have trained the model and only four points,
因为我们只用4个点训练了模型
it cannot be a very good model.
所以这还不是个好模型
So it probably has a pretty high cross-validation error.
它可能有很高的交叉验证误差
We won't show the cross-validation set,
这里我们不给出具体的交叉验证集
but you can pretty much imagine any other random subset of the data.
但你可以用数据的任何随机子集作为交叉验证集
So we plot the cross validation error over here,
所以我们在这里画出交叉验证误差
and now we increase to eight points and we train a linear model again.
现在我们增加到8个点 再次训练这个线性模型
The training error may increase a bit since it's harder to fit eight points than four,
训练误差可能会增加一点 因为8个点比4个点更难拟合
but since we have a slightly better model and we've used more data to train it,
由于我们有一个稍微好一点的模型 并且我们使用了更多的数据来训练它
then maybe the cross validation error has decreased a bit,
那么交叉验证误差可能减少了一点
but not much since it's a linear model trying to fit quadratic data.
但并没有太多 因为它是试图用一个线性模型去拟合二次类型的数据
So here are the training and cross validation errors in the graph,
这是图表中的训练和交叉验证误差
and now we increase to 12 points and we train the model again.
现在增加到12个点 再次训练这个线性模型
So once more, the training error may
再次 因为有更多的训练数据需要拟合
increase a bit since there's more training data to fit,
训练误差可能会再增加一点
but the cross-validation error will also decrease a
因为我们用了更多的训练数据  得到了一个更好的模型
bit since we have a better model trained with more data,
所以交叉验证误差也会减少一点
but it's still won't decrease by much.
但同样不会减少太多
It seems that as we increase the number of points more and more
随着点数的增加
the training error will keep increasing and the testing error will keep decreasing.
训练误差将不断增大而测试误差将不断减小
So if we draw these two curves,
如果我们画这两条曲线
they'll get closer and closer to each other and maybe converge at some point.
它们会越来越靠近 也许会在某个点上收敛
The point they converge should be high anyway,
不管怎样 它们的收敛点应该很高
since we don't expect these models to have small error as the are under fitting.
因为欠拟合 所以我们不会期待这些模型有小的误差
Now let's do the exact same thing with the quadratic model,
现在让我们对二次模型做同样的事
so let's remember that this is the good model.
让我们记住 这是一个好的模型
So training with four points just as before,
所以像以前一样 先用四个点训练
we can do pretty well in the training set so we have a small training error.
我们可以在训练中做得很好 所以会有一个小的训练误差
But since we train the model and very few points,
但是因为我们的训练数据太少
we probably didn't do very well in the cross-validation set,
我们可能在交叉验证集上表现的不太好
so our cross-validation error is large.
所以我们的交叉验证误差比较大
Now if we increase to eight points again,
现在再次增加到8个点
our training error increases since we have more points to fit.
训练误差将会增加，因为有更多的点要拟合
But since our model knows more,
但因为我们的模型通过在更多的点上训练
as it's trained on more points than the cross-validation error has decreased,
知道的更多  交叉验证误差将减少
and if we go to 12 points the same thing happens again.
如果增加到12个点 同样的事情又会发生
Training error increases, cross-validation error decreases.
训练误差增加交叉验证误差减少
So as before, these curves get closer and closer to each other.
所以和以前一样 这些曲线越来越靠近
Except, now they converge to a lower point since
但是 现在因为是个好模型
the model is good and we expect it to have small error.
所以它们将收敛到一个较低的点 我们将会有一个较小误差
Finally, let's do the same thing with the degree six model.
最后 让我们用6次多项式模型做同样的事情
Let's remember that this is a model that overfits,
记住 这是一个过拟合模型
so let's train with four points.
让我们用四个点来训练
Again we can fit for points very easily,
同样 我们可以很容易的拟合这些点
so we have a small training error,
得到一个小的训练误差
and again as we don't have very much formation in four points,
再次 因为这四个点提供的信息太少
this model probably didn't do very well on the cross-validation set,
这个模型可能会在交叉验证集上做得不太好
so we have a large cross-validation error.
我们会有一个大的交叉验证误差
Now if we increase the training set to eight points,
现在如果我们增加到8个点
we have a slightly larger training error and
还和以前一样 我们会得到一个稍大一点的训练误差
a slightly smaller testing error just like before.
和稍小一点的测试误差
Now if we increase the training set to eight points,
现在如果增加到8个点
then we have a slightly larger training error
我们会得到一个稍大一点的训练误差
and a slightly smaller cross-validation error.
和稍小一点的交叉验证误差
This happens again for 12 points as we've seen before,
增加到12个点时  这个现象又会发生   就像以前看到的那样
but now something interesting happens,
但现在有趣的事情发生了
the training error will never grow too large since
训练误差不会增长太大
models that over-fit tend to do very well on the training set,
因为过拟合的模型在训练集上会做的很好
as they can fit it very well.
因为它们很好拟合了训练数据
The cross-validation error will never get too low,
而交叉验证误差则不会太低
since as we've seen,
因为正如我们所见
model that over-fit do not do very well on the cross-validation set.
过拟合的模型在交叉验证集上表现的不太好
So as we increase the number of points,
所以当我们增加训练点数时
these two curves will get closer,
这两条曲线会更靠近一点
but will not converge to the same point,
但不会收敛到同一点
there will always be a distance between them.
它们之间总会保持一定距离
So in summary, here we have our three models the high bias,
总之 这是我们的三个模型  一个高偏差
the good one and the high variance.
一个好模型和一个高方差
Then the high bias or underfitting model,
在高偏差或欠拟合模型中
the curves get close to each other and converts to a high point.
两个曲线彼此逐渐靠近并收敛在高点
In the good model the curves again go close to each other and converge to a low point,
在好模型中 两个曲线彼此逐渐靠近并收敛在低点
and in the high-variance or over fitting model,
而在高方差或过拟合模型中
the curves did not get close to each other.
两个曲线不会彼此逐渐靠近
The training one stays low and the cross-validation one stays high.
训练误差曲线保持在低位而交叉验证的误差曲线保持在高位
So this is a way to tell between underfitting overfitting and just right.
因此这是区分欠拟合和过拟合的一种方法
We just look at the learning curves and see what shape they form.
我们刚才了解了学习曲线并观察了它们的形状